MICHELLE BUCHUKWU OKONICHA

Frontend Developer



13 Bolanle Adams



+2348169391259



michelleokonicha@gmail.con



My Portfolio Website

SKILLS



SOCIAL





witter



inkedIn



Instagram

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A skilled software developer, knowledgeable in React.JS, Javascript, SQL, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, HTML and API consumption. Fast learner and familiar with design tools like Figma and Adobe XD. Amazing client software builder with keen interest in product scalability. Experienced in the tech industry and with the use of different technology tools Highly innovative and fascinated by how technology swiftly can change things, improve lives and ease stress. An advocate and contributor of opensource and volunteer workspaces.

CORE COMPETENCE

Software Programming with Javascript Languange, React framework, SQL, CSS, SASS, BootstrapHTML. Fetching and consumption of APIs for proper web implementation Data Analysis Batchscript Integration Penetration Testing before software product release Data mapping Interpersonal communication skills Fluency in the English language Creative thinker Attention to details. Ability to work effectively in a group Problem solving skills Leadership skills Analytical skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Zuri Chat, Lagos Nigeria Aug 2021- Present

Zuri Chat is a technology web3 communication platform similar to slack. which is fully integrated to work with the DAO/Web3 decentralized system. It makes remote working easy and smooth and also uses NFTs.

- I work as a frontend developer in Zuri chat
- We built zuri chat from the scratch, integrating all features and ensuring it functions properly.
- I work with other developers performing different functions to ensure zuri chat runs well.
- I built the push notification using centrifugal
- O I implemented the features pages
- I teamed up with other developers to implement themes, dark and light mode and other theme selected colors on every zuri chat page.
- I also was the secretary in charge of the DAO/web3 sub team in ensuring the process is integrated as needed.
- I am an active participating member of other sub-teams involved in clean up of the site and fixing of bugs
- I am part of the quality control team to ensure nothing sub-standard is used.

Software Support Zanibal LLC, Lagos Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Zanibal LLC is a Financial technology company that proffers solutions selectively to the Capital Market.

- O I was involved in Batch script Integration
- Pent testing and bugs identification

- Data Analysis MySQI and Postgres database for client software solution.
- Resolution of Client issues regarding the fintech software solution
- Worked on different client databases to ensure system security and proper functioning
- Make use of the Amazon web server (AWS) to host applications
- Train clients on the use of software solutions to provide Send out SQL query based reports to clients
- Send out notifications written as batch scripts, document scripts and templates
- In charge of client on-boarding and settling into the use of the Zanibal software solutions offered
- Work on different system modules to provide updates on newly implemented features
- Document and mass inform clients of newly added features on the system.

Software Engineer Intern HNG, Lagos Nigeria

Aug 2021- October 2021

- Building products with the React frame work, JavaScript, css modules
- Integration with the backend by consuming APIs and hooking
- Worked with different teams to see the product comes up in time
- worked in an agile system involving a lot of collaboration
- Strengthened my use of React.Js
- The internship was very demanding and really tasking. Learnt a lot and how to find and fix bugs
- Ensured every page was responsive and pixel perfect
- Worked on pages functionalities views

Technical Support

Apex Tech

Sep 2020- Dec 2020

- Analyzed root causes of technical and operational malfunctions and provide resolutions.
- Managed flows to ensure timely completion product implementation.
- Monitored all products for problems, taking immediate action where possible and escalating when required.
- Interacted with clients, resolve problems and provide information.
- Resolved and closed issue requests and incidents to ensure high customer satisfaction and positive support outcomes.
- Ensured clients know the current status of their individual projects, by providing updated communications to include estimated timelines of resolution, escalation and other pertinent information.
- Worked with colleagues to ensure clients continuously perceive the company to have world-class service delivery.
- Excellent understanding of client's idea and obsessive attention to details.
- Evaluate current operational processes and recommend improvements.
- Work closely with peers on the marketing and sales teams to provide operational support and ensure alignment.

Technical Support Intern

Apex Tech

Sep 2020- Sep 2020

- Worked on Startup software development projects Reviewed all applications and websites we build to ensure proper debugging and on-boarding. Attended all board and executive meetings on behalf of the company. Scheduled all executive meetings. Right- hand person of the CEO. Carried-out operational activities. Met clients to negotiate and elaborate company's structure. Wordpress support as most websites were built with wordpress. I supported the websites and fixed issues when they arose. Managed some products as well as projects. Head of Digital EUC Homes, Lagos Nigeria May 2020- Aug 2020 Online customer representation. Supervised all banners and fliers production. Advertised the company online. Attracted sales. Wrote all company's content both copies and contents. Answered all customer queries, complaints, suggestions and inquiries. In-charge of company's whatsapp platform. Support Analyst Twinstar Industries Limited, Nigeria March 2019-Apr 2020
 - Made calls to customers and prospective.
 - Attended to customers complaints, orders and suggestions.
 - Made samples for customers.
 - Planned the dispatch of goods daily.
 - Ensured that customers stay.
 - Made sure to find out why a customer left.
 - Received calls from enquirers.

EDUCATION

University of Nigeria, Nsukka

Microbiology/Biochemistry

Jan 2014-July 2018

Zuri Technology Institute

Software Engineering

March 2021-July 2021

Frontend Development. Languages learnt: CSS, Javascript, React. JS

FreeCode Camp

Software Engineering

March 2021-Dec 2021

Frontend Development. Languages learnt: CSS, Javascript,React.JS

Y combinator Startup School

